hello my name is green and welcome back
to hermitcraft i'm trying to fly in my
base and do my intros not working out so
last episode we had the very important
machine of the
mumbo's mustache remover i i still
doesn't quite have a name i did read the
comments but didn't really see any that
took my fancy unfortunately
so this has been a really important
project and i'm so happy that a lot of
you loved what went on there but we're
actually gonna put this away for a
little while because we can't take his
mustache away every single episode can
we but there is more things to do so
what i have done today already is i've
gone on a quartz hunt and i spent about
an hour grinding quartz so i think for
the start of this episode we're gonna go
on a little grinding session time-lapse
thing and i'm gonna talk to you about
some of my plans and stuff for
hermitcraft maybe answer a few questions
as well
now the reason that i'm doing this whole
time lapse thing and maybe it's going a
little bit quickly is because i don't
actually have an awful long time to make
this episode i'm going away for a few
days and trying to make a hermitcraft
episode quickly for me
is about as difficult as rocket science
because i usually take two to three days
to make every single episode i just put
that much time into it and it's as
simple as that i have to do all my
grinding all the preparation all of the
extra little bits that i do on the side
and then some building it is just hugely
time consuming and then i'm also working
on other projects as well amongst other
things so i find it really difficult to
make a hermit craft quickly so this time
i'm including a bit of grinding in here
as well i also thought i'd answer a few
questions noah jordan kish says what's
an average recording session like well i
kind of just went over that but there's
a huge amount of preparation like
getting all the resources i need to plan
out my episodes i really really think
about every single thing that i want to
do but a lot of the humor that comes
from each episode happens on the spot
it's not pre-planned so i come up with
the main plot points and what i want to
accomplish
but then it all goes haywire from there
eric arakilian says now that you've
taken mumbo's mustache away what's next
that is a really good question because
now that i've accomplished my main goal
in this series
i don't know what to do i'm going to
come up with many more storylines and
things that i want to happen
i'm just not sure what that is yet and
i'm going to enjoy finding out
ron defrane says if you aren't paltry
man then who is well it's simple it's
the man in the chicken costume
and esturo says which country would you
like to visit in the futuro well i'm
pretty sure you mean future
and there are so many it's so difficult
to choose but if i had to name a few i
really really want to go to the
philippines new zealand australia canada
all of the anglo-sphere basically i love
love my canadians about straight as new
zealand's because we're kind of similar
but then i also want to go outside of my
comfort zone i want to visit india and
places that i might get more of a
culture shock from
basically everywhere i guess is the easy
answer to say but there's a few few that
i really want to visit commando pando
says hey green now i was wondering on a
scale of 1 to 10 how good are your art
skills
well if you've seen my drawing badly
series you'll know that my art skills
are particularly
awful anyway i think that probably wraps
up this one hour grinding session for
quartz quite nicely so let's get back
into the server
alright now that that's over let's go
and restock because the reason i was
getting all this quartz in the first
place is because my little shack sells
more quartz than anything else and it's
actually been out of stock for quite a
long time
let's see if we could punch him up
missed him
yeah i thought i thought i could hit him
on the head okay let's oh we got a
couple diamonds let's pop all this in
here and that's not all i have i
actually have
lots and lots of nether quartz this
should sell out in no time at all
wow i actually got way more than i
thought
i'm pretty sure that this is a much
faster way of getting diamonds
than actually going and mining diamonds
i'm not sure well this took an hour to
get so there's two full chests full how
many diamonds is that there's about 40
diamonds worth of quartz in here maybe
more more like 50 diamonds so hopefully
this will all sell out quickly and we'll
have a stack of diamonds and i'm pretty
sure i wouldn't make 50 diamonds just
for mining although i can't be sure i
haven't mined diamonds for a really long
time there we go that was a lot more
quartz i'm so grateful that i haven't
decided to build anything out of quartz
for this series because that is an
absolute nightmare to get my hands on
but it's a pretty good money-making
scheme i think
this is possibly my favorite thing that
i've made in hermitcraft you know apart
from the mumbo mustache removal machine
it's just nice it's just a nice little
cart that sells whatever i've got going
on for me but i do think that at some
point i will have to expand my my little
uh shop empire i think at the same time
since halloween is over
i'm going to remove these horns up here
i want to keep my pickle shop as clean
as possible and i don't think anyone can
complain now that halloween is over it
might be even time to make this a
christmas pickle maybe maybe it's too
early is it too early for christmas
stuff i i love christmas so i i think
the earlier the better personally
now we just got to replace these eyes
they look a bit weird like oh no this
whole thing is mate what
are you really trying to have a go at me
from there
look how far away i am from him
this is ridiculous
i cannot place it in i'm just gonna have
to get rid of them all there we go
his face is back to normal i don't want
to see any more of these
and he's kind of back to normal i think
he looks different actually very
slightly in fact i might have missed a
slight bit
i don't know whether that candle was
there before or not i think maybe not i
remember that i have a little list of
things that i wanted to do in the
hermitcraft series
however i have already done some of my i
guess to-do list my bucket list
so let's go and knock some of those off
i haven't actually been in his for a
while this is where i started my entire
series i very rarely come in here now i
wonder what i should do with it or just
leave it as like a little nostalgia trip
i don't know
okay so this was my list of things to do
uh i've done number two i've done number
six
take mumbo's mustache
away it's done so i only have a few more
things feature every hermit on the
server at least once i'm pretty sure
i've nearly done that i've got just a
few more hermits to do a little segment
with but i don't want to force it it's
when it becomes when it comes naturally
that's the most important thing
make a proper redstone storage system
now i don't know how
interested i am in doing this anymore i
might actually remove this because i
honestly can't be bothered and create a
base in every area i haven't even
finished my one base so i don't know how
that's gonna happen let's add a couple
more shall we
maybe i should come up with a couple
more sometime if you have any ideas of
what could go on my bucket list please
let me know as long as it's not
something out of my comfort zone
the other thing that i really need to do
is work out what on earth i'm going to
do with this giant hole under my base i
don't know why i made it i think it's
just because i had a beacon and i was
just excited that i could do this and i
also thought that i might be able to get
a few more diamonds out of the ground
but it's dry there's nothing left there
are no diamonds i've i've i'm i'm all
the way down look i've even
i got so desperate that i even started
just digging under here there are none
left it's unbelievable there should in
theory be way more
but i i've just yeah i've just mined it
all dry
but i'm thinking that there needs to be
something done with this area in general
this is a big space
and i'm sure i'll come up with something
uh the only problem is it's such a mess
i need to figure out where the exit is
i think i can go out no i can't go out
that way wait can i
no no i can't that's just a bit of water
[Music]
okay never again never down here again
never again
also today we are participating in the
kill a tango challenge over there is
where i made my little infinity room to
participate in his competition and all
you have to do is kill him there are
certain rules but they were kind of
ignored
so i want to show you everyone's
submission except the very last one in
order it was cub then impulse then me
then doc then x and i'm going to briefly
show you a montage a little clip of
every single person's submission and i'm
going to cut out everything else in
between but if you want to see the full
thing i recommend you go and have a look
on tango's channel
hit the button and then
then just yeah ensues right it does it
does okay
i'm ready look good luck i'm going in
i'm putting it about 50 this thing fails
so all right here we go
three two one
oh oh water okay
i'm under water
now the clock is ticking so that's the
first nightmare
first nightmare is drowning
use of fear i like this
taking damage
drowning
then being crushed no
sand in my face
and then
okay
wait for it pushed out the back
exit thing here
slowly
final nightmare coming in oh very slowly
oh
there it is
[Applause]
oh man that was fantastic
don't kill gasty claws
oh the bubble vader
oh
i got hit by some kind of person
man
what's in there tango uh oh it's a
drought with a trident
okay more more bubble vader oh your
favorite
[Laughter]
he didn't
survive the tnt unfortunately the
pistons kind of pre-fired there which
was a bit of my concern so there's one
last bit you're actually going to die
twice today because uh all right that
didn't kick you over like it was
supposed to so come back here there all
right yeah feel free to let go of the
mouse and stuff
oh
[Laughter]
negative points that almost killed the
judges
[Laughter]
typically you'd be down to half a heart
right now this guy might take a while so
uh this is the most
i wasn't really expecting an audience i
thought it was just going to be like me
and the judges and i kind of wish that i
didn't get part of this because mine's
super lame now but anyway i'm going to
just uh oh my gosh
okay i'm ready i'm ready look at this
guy
right
so tango i need you to stand
right here
by the way i have the judges in my head
they're they're like invading my brain
right now yeah so that the judges can
experience this with tanks this is a
first-person experience only apparently
yeah this is and so everyone here kind
of just has to pretend like they know
what's going on all right
are you ready tango i'm sure i don't
know what's gonna happen okay
so
what's gonna happen is you're gonna die
instantly
absolutely instantly okay
okay all right when you're ready click
the button
i can't wait
okay we have the potato
whoa
oh no
oh
you know green
like you right now
i am walking believe it or not
you are officially dead by the way that
that's it for you you are you are dead
and this is the voice of the body mode
okay
so this is what the afterlife looks like
oh yeah this is this is the afterlife
and tango tango listen to me this is the
afterlife you can have whatever you
want i would like eyesight please
you can't have that
sometimes you can't tell i am completely
surrounded in a white glob of
nothingness
you would like a glass of lemonade thank
you
i can give you something that will help
uh okay
can i i mean i could punch but i know
that would be bad right
i think you know what to do now that
you're in uh
you've sorted out
slash kill what
oh no
fine
oh good job
okay now no one go down there you will
actually die
i'm scared man since you put on the suit
i'm very scared of you
i wish i was dead sooner
yeah i like the suit extra points for
that that was a nice addition yep
all right wait for it wait wait foreign
are you here you see us come on you can
find it
so that was an awful lot of fun i'm glad
i did participate i didn't even get
disqualified somehow the judges didn't
mark me too high compared to everyone
else but i think the right person won
impulse had by far
the best and this has appeared since
then in my base
let's see what it says
frequent flyer green tech to the skies
would like to honor your many frequent
flyer miles and ludicrous contributions
you've made to our business
oh it's
it's not quite christmas
but it certainly feels like christmas
because i spent so much money
so many diamonds on
rockets because of my stupid rocket
habits
tango has given me a shulker box full of
rockets this is the best i mean it's not
going to last long but
he's got a loyal customer in me i tell
you well until i can make my own rockets
that is
as you can see i started working on more
stripes i just haven't quite had the
time to do the bills that i want to but
i also had another idea with something
on this part of the base now this is
where i spend most of my time but yet it
is one of the worst looking parts of the
build and this in particular is not
looking that great and a simple solution
i thought
would be to give it a bit of a spruce up
and that would include just highlighting
the elevator a little bit with some cyan
terracotta but also this is an issue
because this is my out box this is what
i sent to mumbo but this is my inbox so
i don't think mumbo really thought this
through too well so i thought what i'd
do
is i would divert this off to the side
where i don't use any space at all and
that would free up my outbox but i can't
help but think this is linked up somehow
is it as simple as that there's nothing
nothing fancy
nothing fancy at all okay
so this isn't a trap chest or anything
there's just as soon as there's
something in it it detects it
i'm even i can replicate this
it's probably going to trigger a lot of
people that this is gray but i honestly
don't want it to stand out too much so
it might be a different color but that's
because i really don't want this
fluorescent white to stand out because
it is going to just jut out of nowhere
so now i've just got to divert this
over here
which may be easier than i thought
yeah it was as simple as that it was
really easy
and then i can just get rid of this
and then i just need a sign in here
and that should do it as as soon as you
send an item it should pop straight down
but there's only one way to find out
really
and that is head to mumbo's base
would you look at that he's still got
mail
[Laughter]
i have been here many times and i've
never seen the items fly up like that
where did all of these come from
oh my goodness
did that one chicken do all of that or
are there still chickens in the system
laying eggs
oh i need to i need to put an end to
this no more no more
it's a real bummer to send all of these
eggs elsewhere
let's send the frequent flyer book all
the way to my base shall we
okay the backlog is now finished
hopefully that should be the end of the
chickens
and now his
mail system should work
should work well i think yep that i
think that's the first time i've seen
his beacon a normal color
i love flying past and seeing in mumbo's
little face in there but just look just
think and imagine for a second how many
projects we can fit in these layers it's
going to be absolutely fantastic
and there it is that was pretty easy
and then we just need to link up this
redstone
oh oh
no
i hope that didn't cause any lasting
damage
so you remember when i said even i could
do this redstone
i can't really remember what it looked
like at all
was it something like this
but that doesn't make sense at all
how did how did it detect it
what did it do it looks something like
this
why am i so i didn't even put it
it didn't even put it in line
even if i had got it right i got it
wrong
oh today's not been my day
i kinda want to look
at mumbos because that might help me out
mumbo's got something completely
different to this going on
i don't know what's going on anymore i
might just i might just cover this up
and pretend like it's all good
but really it's not
i tell you what
i'm gonna ask for help basically
i don't have enough space to write so
i've gotta go i've got to try and make
this as distinct as possible
and i also don't have any levels if you
want levels these days you've got to go
up to the pigman farm if you want to go
up to the pigman farm you got to use
this thing up we go
i love this machine it's a bit over the
top because there was nothing wrong with
what we already had in fact this may be
even slower because i used to just fly
up
but
just the way things work on this server
and here they come
here comes the xp walking in
oh it's so awful
that'll do me for now
that's not a safe landing at all it's
it's
it said say fall
that wasn't safe
i could use a book and quill but i think
it's going to be much funnier to try and
put as a little note as possible
okay
i did my best hi broke out box by moving
it please help g
oh i don't like that sound at all
all right let's send the letter on
and i'll let mumbo know
i kind of like this this is much better
than it used to be it used to be such a
mess
that's what i think really sets us apart
mumbo makes the redstone but i can
actually make it look semi-decent so
yeah i'm quite happy with this how this
looks at the moment
i could even do a little hatch here
now there's something else going on on
the server that i kind of want to talk
about because i personally find it
hilarious so you might remember a long
time ago and yeah there's still like a
fight going on from this so i helped cub
make this axe in the log shop owned by
ren okay
now ren is selling a stack of logs for
two diamonds which i think is too much
money because i'm poor
so
you know he's he's actually making some
some diamonds here but
i personally think it's too expensive so
i helped cub make this the undercut shop
so he got evicted so they made the
undercut barge owned by concorp and it's
a really cool looking build and it's
full of logs the only problem is
they are
trying to stock it up but ren comes
along
and buys all of the stock now it's
stocked up at the moment but this time
tomorrow
ren will have bought all of these and i
mean
all of these
and it's a war of attrition at this
point who is going to crack first are
they going to get bored of logging down
all of these blocks or is ren going to
get bored of mining diamonds and buying
them all
who knows
but
i see an opportunity here to get rent
back for what he did to our base ages
ago now you might remember we made like
a little list and he is on the list he's
in fact he's the only person on the list
maybe
just maybe if we could get the concorp's
permission
i'm thinking
we could rig this we could rig this
really good
so ren would come along he'd do his
morning routine taking the logs
and replacing them with diamonds
but we replaced these with a trapped
chest and boom the whole thing
goes up
in a an explosion of great magnitude
wren doesn't know what's hit him and
every everybody loses
except us because we get to laugh
anyway i don't know if that's entirely
possible i don't think it's quite good
form to
to do all that kind of explosion but we
definitely owe ren and i wonder if
concord would be in on that i would even
volunteer to remake this exactly how it
is if they would let me
so that could be a lot of fun because
i'm pretty sure ren is the only one
using this shop
anyway that's it for me everyone thank
you very much for watching again
apologies about this episode not being
quite as chock full as i normally do
very very pushed for time today however
i hope you still enjoyed it and i will
see you in the next episode where
who knows what we're gonna do please
comment what should we do
bye